#### Blanca MANCILLA

4265, rue Jean-Brillant Montréal (Québec) H3T 1P2, Canada +1.514.591.2007

Email: blancalmancilla@gmail.com
Blog: superspreadsheet.wordpress.com
github: https://github.com/bluciam

Written, spoken: English, French, Spanish.

Other: German, B1 level, currently in Goethe Institut.



LinkedIn

## **Professional Profile**

I have +10 years of experience in IT and over a year in Web development. I want to use my skills in coding, problem solving, design, writing, documentation, formalization, leadership, lectureship and communication in a development team. I am always learning and experimenting with current technologies, attending MeetUps, or on Twitter.

# Computer skills snapshot

Web programming in Ruby on Rails, testing, CSS and Bootstrap, HTML. Open source development tools, Linux, scripting, git, github, bitbucket, LTEX. Teaching knowledge in C, C++, JSP, java, haskell, ArcGIS, geographical information systems, human computer interaction, information systems, computer graphics.

#### Current

2012–2015 Consultant, Montreal, Canada

- · Web developer:
  - From design to deployment as sole developer in Ruby on Rails for a Montreal startup (on going).
  - Front-end development including own design using CSS and HTML:
     http://vinka-creations.bitballoon.com.
- · Technical Writer: rewrite developers' interviews as reports and grant proposals.

#### Research Software

**SuperSpreadSheet** (S<sup>3</sup>), https://github.com/bluciam/superspreadsheet

The purpose of this project was to demonstrate the use of contextual electronic documents: case study, the multi-spreadsheet. It covered conception, research, design and implementation.

Anita Conti Mapping Server, https://github.com/bluciam/anita-jsp-2005

The ACMS project was developed as a proof of concept. Development iterations had to accommodate the constant change of requirements, tools and research discoveries. It was successful in its purpose.

TransLucid Project, http://sourceforge.net/projects/translucid/

As a team member, I was part of the design and planning stages of creating the TransLucid language. I devised the documentation structure and tailored it to different audiences. As the first user, I was the main interactive tester of the system.

#### Education

1999-2004	PhD, Computer Science, UNSW, Sydney, Australia
1993-1995	MSc, Geomatic Sciences, Laval University, Québec, Canada
1992-1993	French as a second language, Laval University, Québec, Canada
1990	Seminar on Research, Summer Program, SUNY at Stony Brook, USA
1989-1991	BSc, Computer Electronic Science, Iona College, NY, USA
1984-1988	BEng, Computer Systems Engineering (four of five years), Industrial University of Santander (UIS), Colombia

### **Previous Positions**

- 2004–2016 Faculty Member, University of New South Wales (UNSW), Australia
  - · Theses Supervisor, assessor, advisor; Lecturer (Computer Science).
  - · Researcher, team member, documentation writer, software evaluator.
  - · Assignment conception, specification, deployment and marking.
- 2009–2012 Faculty Member, University of Technology, Sydney (UTS), Australia
  - · Lecturer, curriculum redesigner, specification writer.
- 1993–1995 **Student Assistant** (Remote Sensing), Laval University, Québec, Canada
  - · Lecturer-tutor, software lab instructor, marker.
- 1991–1992 **System Administrator**, IBM AS/400, Electro-Alloys, NY, USA

# **Conference and Workshops Organization**

2001-2002	International Conference on Distributed Communities on the Web, DCW 2002
	Local Arrangements Chair: Webmaster; budget and conference manager.
2000-2002	Women in Computing, UNSW, Director and founder:
	Liaison between community stakeholders; conception of events.
2000-2003	Girls in Science and Technology Workshops, UNSW, Founder organizer:
	Workshops on HTML, lego mindstorms and iMovie; host.

## Publications, http://plaice.web.cse.unsw.edu.au/~plaice/archive/BLM

Total	28	Books	1	Book Chapters	1
		Journal Articles	5	Theses	2
		Conference Articles	17	Compilations	2